David Melkonian
25807 Laramie Dr
Novi, MI 48374
United States
248-207-2001
davemelk.com
davemelk@gmail.com
https://www.linkedin.com/in/davemelk/

I'm a User Experience and User Interface specialist with a CUA from Human Factors International. I've created responsive design frameworks by hand, created graphic design systems and integrated them directly with front end code. I've created wireframes, graphic comps, design systems, working prototypes and fully coded POCs. I am fluent in Photoshop, Illustrator, Sketch and Figma. I've been fortunate to work on many applications of all sizes. Some include the Delta Dental MySmileCoverage site, Delta's Dental's Member Portal Delta's SaaS product Roosevelt Solutions, the HealthCare.gov product, Blue Cross Blue Shield of Michigan's bcbsm.com, and mibcn.com along with countless others.

My career has included enterprise software delivery with companies/initiatives such as HealthCare.gov, Blue Cross Blue Shield, United Healthcare, Meridian Health, Delta Dental of Michigan, Ford Motor Company, General Motors and more. In addition to my current role, my previous roles include delivery manager, technical lead, accessibility lead, user experience and user interface designer/developer/consultant and technical writer. I have designed, built and delivered some of the most robust, efficient and accessible software the industry has to offer. My experience as a developer, designer, tech lead, as well as manager, has helped me to be an effective and efficient problem solver and an exceptional business partner. I've helped deliver millions of dollars in revenue for many companies but it's never accomplished alone.

I've always been a team-first leader and contributor. Hiring and working alongside people who challenge not only me, but also challenge the team to be better has been a proven formula for success. I've forged many wonderful relationships through the years with brilliant and creative people. I've learned something from every single person I've worked with. Traveling extensively for business and managing teams all over the world opened my eyes to just how critical it is to be transparent, inclusive, supportive, empathetic and impactful

SKILLS, TOOLING, SOFTWARE, CONCEPT PROFICIENCIES

- HTML
- CSS
- Typescript
- Javascript
- ReactJs
- Angular
- Razor
- iQuery
- UX/XD/CX/IXD/UI
- Responsive and adaptive design
- Wireframing
- Prototyping
- Journey Mapping
- User Personas
- Peer Leadership

- UI architecture, design and strategy
- Information Architecture
- Figma
- Sketch
- Photoshop
- Illustrator
- UX design and strategy
- UX design and development
- Project Management
- Product Ownership
- Product Management
- Strategic leadership
- Digital accessibility expertise
- Stakeholder Interviews
- Team Collaboration

- Team Leadership
- Management
- SPAs
- Micro Frontends
- Microservices
- REST
- API
- AJAX
- Github
- VersionOne
- Subversion
- Jira
- Confluence
- Contextual Inquiry
- Task flows
- User flows
- Empathy maps
- User research
- Usability Testing
- Heuristic Reviews
- Technical consulting

- A/B Testing
- Color blindness testing
- Bootstrap
- Foundation
- Accessible coding practices
- VersionOne
- MS Word
- MS Excel
- MS Powerpoint
- aXe
- WAVE
- Micro frontends
- Microservices
- Wordpress
- Umbraco
- Magnolia
- JAWS
- Voiceover
- InVision
- Azure
- Razor

EDUCATION

Oakland University Rochester, MI Bachelor Of Arts - English

CERTIFICATIONS

Certified ScrumMaster® (Scrum Alliance)
Certified Usability Analyst (Human Factors International)
ITIL Foundation Certificate in IT Service Management (Peoplecert/Axelos)

EXPERIENCE

DEWPOINT INC.

LANSING, MI

United States

May 2016 - PRESENT

User Interface and User Experience Specialist

- Created visual style guide using Angular / HTML / CSS for Delta Dental of Michigan's Roosevelt Solutions SaaS platform (DDMI)
- Created React / Node application POC for event registration app (Dewpoint)
- Created Angular / Node application POC for event registration app (Dewpoint)
- Created React / Node application for personal portfolio
- Built front end of an event registration app using .NET/JS/Azure and an Umbraco CMS (Dewpoint)
- Built out accessibility practice to ensure all DDMI applications adhered to ADA standards (DDMI)
- Created a robust, platform-wide accessibility development and testing practice (DDMI)
- Managed a team of User Experience designers and User Interface Developers (DDMI)

- Developed within a Magnolia CMS to build out a custom shopping experience (DDMI)
- Created Freemarker templates to allow configurability with a Magnolia CMS (DDMI)
- Used Sketch files to convert and build out comps with HTML/CSS/Angular (DDMI)
- Created HTML/CSS/Angular component pattern libraries to support software products (DDMI)
- Created the enterprise standards and guidelines for HTML/CSS/Accessibility for UI developers (DDMI)
- Led Delta Dental of Michigan's UX/UI council (DDMI)
- Ensured applications adhered to marketing and branding guidelines (DDMI)
- Conducted focus groups with stakeholders to understand needs and goals (Lansing BWL)
- Evaluated and wireframed new ideas based on user feedback and testing (Lansing BWL)
- Redesigned a Power BI executive dashboard (Lansing BWL)
- Conducted discovery sessions with president, tech leads and development team (ONU One)
- Created proposal for creating a user experience for a 3d software product (ONU One)
- Created annotated wireframes detailing an end-to-end process for the 3d product (ONU One)

MERIDIAN HEALTH PLAN
Detroit, MI
June 2015 – May 2016
Manager of Application Delivery

- Managed a web team of 20 across numerous project tracks
- · Built a user experience discipline that previously had not existed within the company
- Created strategy and methodology for user experience and user interface design
- Drove ux creative direction for web portals, corporate sites and mobile applications
- Wrote job descriptions for all user experience and interface design roles in corporate job postings
- Implemented the Agile Scrum framework for rapid application development
- Collaborated with the corporate CIO and IT president on strategic decisions
- Provided strategic direction for a mobile and web development team
- Worked in conjunction with web content strategist on information architecture
- Worked with corporate communications to ensure proper web messaging

OPTUM / UNITED HEALTHCARE GROUP Southfield, MI October 2011 – June 2015 Software Development Manager

- Spent 4 months consulting on the Federal Exchange (HealthCare.gov) identifying UI and UX issues and delivering prescribed solutions
- Performed heuristic reviews of HealthCare.gov to identify the top 10 usability issues
- Managed team of 30 across numerous project tracks
- Created/staffed/trained dev teams in Manila, New Delhi, Hyderabad, Minnesota, Boston and Seattle
- Consulted internal and external groups about responsive and accessible front end coding
- Interviewed over 75 candidates for web developer positions
- Served as subject matter expert for all of UHG regarding HTML/CSS development
- Created responsive design component framework from scratch using HTML/CSS/AngularJS
- Led team of developers to deliver responsive web design code for rapid project development
- Led UX/UI/technical strategy sessions

- Integrated development team with design and ux team to review personas, user journeys and task flows for technical feasibility and appropriate user experience controls
- Conducted regular process and standards sessions to ensure our UX principles remained intact from concept to build

BLUE CROSS BLUE SHIELD OF MICHIGAN
Detroit, MI
August 2005 – October 2011
Senior Application Developer

- Interview potential employee candidates
- Maintain intranet search results page
- Create streaming media presentations
- Performed significant maintenance on BCBSM.com and MiBCN.com
- Created a new BCBSM Foundation site which won a bronze Wilmer Shields Rich Award
- Created numerous intranet sites, including CEO Dan Loepp's Website
- Assembled streaming video platform for CEO Dan Loepp streaming media Webcasts
- Created numerous dynamic forms using ColdFusion
- Build dynamic websites using ColdFusion
- Redesigned division website to make more easily navigable
- Created new layout for online manuals
- Created interactive training guides
- Created division sub-site for new BlueHealthConnection product

Ford Motor Company (contract from ASG Renaissance)
Dearborn, MI
August 1999 - August 2005
Technical Writer

- Created Web-based, interactive training guides used in website
- Maintained online screen help for prototype inventory software
- Maintained training documentation for prototype inventory software training courses
- Created/designed help and training documentation and training course for 2 vehicle scheduling apps
- Wrote global bulletins alerting users of software modifications

EDS

Troy MI May 1998 - August 1999 Project Manager

- Created and maintained general communications Website for GM Service Operations
- Performed planning and scheduling for midsize and full-size truck technical writing and service readiness groups using ABT Project Workbench software
- Provided customers with baseline-versus-actual reports, project status reports and recommendations
- Created risk assessments and contingency plans for service manual development deliverables

- Assisted in creating and maintaining a work breakdown structure document for service manual development
- Complied with ISO-9001 procedures as part of ISO Certification initiative
- Interviewed potential candidates using behavioral interviewing techniques